<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-18T11:27:46-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Elias Fong</title><subtitle>Personal site of a Elias Fong, a developer based out of Boston,  containing tutorials, reviews, and other posts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Phantom Thread: Love and Desire</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/18/Desire-Phantom-Thread" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phantom Thread: Love and Desire" /><published>2018-01-18T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-18T11:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/18/Desire-Phantom-Thread</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/18/Desire-Phantom-Thread">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Phantom Thread, and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“When you &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt;, how does it feel? And when you &lt;strong&gt;desire&lt;/strong&gt;, how is it different?”&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Esther Perel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phantom Thread is a film about the relationship between Reynolds Woodcock, an English couture dressmaker from the 1950’s, and Alma, his most recent romantic interest. The film begins with the world that Reynolds inhabits- one where he is the center of attention of many women, and where his attention is solely focused on his work. Reynolds is a man of particular habits- ones that Alma will later describe as “fussy”- and has a sensitive relationship with his work, which he connects to his childhood and his mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Alma first appears, she is a waitress at a countryside restaurant. They circle one another with wandering eyes, and Reynolds asks her to dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alma experiences many of Reynold’s peculiarities right away: from his fixation on his deceased mother, his sister’s inattention to privacy, and Reynold’s singular focus on dress-making. However, during the series of uncomfortable interactions, it is revealed that she does not think much of herself, but Reynolds finds her to be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-alma.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alma in an extravagant pink dress&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, she begins to discover more about their relationship, as well as Reynold’s lifestyle. She loves his attention at first, her eyes following him as he organizes little details in the fabric as he dresses her like a doll. But then, she begins to feel more and more like a doll, a disposable object, a lifeless toy that can be cast into a corner without a second thought. Reynolds is surrounded by fawning women, and Alma begins to experience a growing jealousy from within her. His peculiar nature is undirected, but distant, and almost feels spiteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She discovers that he is weak after exhausting himself with his passion for dressmaking, and that he needs him most in his weakness. After an argument over dinner, she decides to poison Reynolds with a concoction of mushrooms in tea. He falls ill over the next day. After she nurses him back to health, he realizes that he is missing something from a shared life, and asks her to marry him in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is an account of Reynold’s distaste for her habits and his cruel lashing as he begins to experience jealousy himself. The story ends with a repeating cycle of Alma’s poisoning and nursing Reynolds back to health- the two of them knowing that they will come back to each other when they are weak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-diner-scene.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reynolds asks Alma to dinner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you reconcile the opposing needs of love and desire? This crisis is at the center of modern relationships and comes from our demand for both within a single relationship. Psychotherapist Esther Perel says that we want the security and stability of a committed relationship, but also the adventure of desire. Desire, which is sustained by mystery and discovery, opposes the quality of immutability in a committed relationship. And it is from these opposing forces that we see the characters of Phantom Thread struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their jealousy, which ebbs and flows over the course of their relationship, is one of the more tangible forms of desire that we witness. Whenever Reynolds loses himself in his work, Alma feels a growing distance, and whenever Alma acts in a way that Reynolds does not anticipate, he feels unwanted. However, this is something that he understands about himself, whether or not he has control over it. “Marriage would make me deceitful, and I don’t ever want that”, he says. When Alma asks him more about it, he explains that expectations of others is dangerous, and results in a loss of control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-alma-on-stairs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alma on the staircase&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his mind, expectations can make you deceitful because you will try to push someone toward the mold you have created for them without realizing it, simply because you expect certain behavior. It is in the nature of expectation that this occurs, because we are limited in how we understand anything outside of ourselves, yet love pushes us to try to understand. We can develop some reasonable level of understanding, but to completely understand another person is impossible. When there is no end to the nuances in your own behavior, how can you expect to fully understand another’s?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alma acts on her jealousy by posioning Reynolds, physically forcing him to need her. “I want you flat on your back. Helpless, tender, open with only me to help,” she says. His poison, on the other hand, is in the flailing anger in his words, and the cold disposition he applies toward her. They both carry the same need of being needed, and frivolousness with the love of the other. And in their inability to use words to express these things, a pattern emerges- a cycle of love and desire, of needing and being needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps in recognizing this cycle that their relationship begins to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine read tarot cards for me a few weeks back while she visited from Germany. One of the cards she drew was called the “Wheel of Fortune”, which contained a picture of a wheel with entities moving up one side and down the other. The meaning, she explained, was that by recognizing the cyclical nature of things, we can can take more control over our fates. When you are at the bottom of the wheel- at the low points in life- by remembering that it is part of a larger cycle, the virtue of patience can remind you to endure the bad and continue your search for the good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These cycles do not only occur within relationships of course, and Alma even says, “being in love with him makes life no great mystery.” Perhaps it is in recognizing the ups and downs and in accepting that we cannot fully understand others that we can build meaningful relationships where we can love, change, desire, and share a life with another person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-end-credits.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alma being fitted for a dress by Reynolds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Phantom Thread, and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/phantom-thread.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern Relationships and Murakami’s Sputnik Sweetheart</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/media/writing/philosophy/2018/01/15/Modern-Relationships-and-Murakamis-Sputnik-Sweetheart" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern Relationships and Murakami's Sputnik Sweetheart" /><published>2018-01-15T13:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T13:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/media/writing/philosophy/2018/01/15/Modern-Relationships-and-Murakamis-Sputnik-Sweetheart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/media/writing/philosophy/2018/01/15/Modern-Relationships-and-Murakamis-Sputnik-Sweetheart">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the book Sputnik Sweetheart, and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of the word “Longing”, what do you think about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine hands reaching toward one another, their skin never touching. Or standing on some towering building and looking for the small shape of a place I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think of someone particular when you hear that word? Or is it a place that you haven’t been?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Murakami’s &lt;em&gt;Sputnik Sweetheart&lt;/em&gt;, every character is a satellite- a small, metal object, hurling through the emptiness of space. The narrator, who is in love with Sumire, watches as she falls in love with an older woman named Miu, who she refers to as her “Sputnik Sweetheart”. They are all intimate with one another in different ways, but between each of them, an uncrossible distance remains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And it came to me then. That we were wonderful traveling companions but in the end no more than lonely lumps of metal in their own separate orbits. From far off they look like beautiful shooting stars, but in reality they’re nothing more than prisons, where each of us is locked up alone, going nowhere. When the orbits of these two satellites of ours happened to cross paths, we could be together. Maybe even open our hearts to each other. But that was only for the briefest moment. In the next instant we’d be in absolute solitude. Until we burned up and became nothing.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sputnik referred to in the story is Sputnik 2, a Russian satellite that was launched into orbit in 1957 with a dog named Laika as its passenger. The word “Sputnik” enters the story from a miscommunication between Miu and Sumire, and is lovingly used to refer to Miu. When thinking of the same little satellite, the narrator pictures the dog gazing out into the “infinite loneliness of space”, looking for something in the blackness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These images set the tone of the story early on, and we watch as the characters pass out of each other’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/sputnik-laika.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Laika in the Sputnik 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did you write when you last wrote about someone you know? For me, it was during the last snowstorm, and I was in my room, watching the spotted darkness pass over my window. I wrote about a girl with brown hair that I once walked through the Isabella Stewart Gardner museum with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum has an interesting history: beginning with Gardner’s will for the building to never change after her death, and later involving a theft in the 1990’s. When you visit, now, you’ll find empty spaces in walls with the shadows of paintings, and frames with nothing in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote about the time we walked through those halls on a summer night, when she admired the old frames, while I was captivated by the empty spaces. Now, whenever I go, I feel like a ghost, searching for lost time- still captivated by the empty spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murakami writes in the same ways. His characters are always recurring in his novels- a man who has affairs with older women, a girl who stares at the moon- and are written as if he knew them. The metaphors he uses feel like memories rather than just imagery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Who can really distinguish the sea and what’s reflected in it? Or tell the difference between the falling rain and loneliness?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His intimacy with these characters feels like the written form of the kind of thoughts that come at night. I can imagine him laying in his bed, awake- his eyes staring at the ceiling- before he turns on a lamp at his bedside to write down a passing thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/sputnik-murakami.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Murakami&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease in which modern relationships comprise of missed connections is a paradox that is concerning to me. When Murakami published this book in 2001- five years after the rise of the mobile phone- the rate in which the world was becoming connected by technology had become exponential. Three years later, Facebook was introduced, and grew into a world-wide phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1960’s Stanley Milgram ran the “small world experiment”, in which the theory of &lt;em&gt;Six Degrees Of Separation&lt;/em&gt; was examined. In the theory, everyone in the world is connected by five intermediate acquaintances- so that if I count all my friends, friend’s friend’s, and so on, I would be connected to all 7 billion people on the planet. In 2011, Facebook analyzed their data, and found that this number is decreasing- from six degrees to five- and is continuing to do so as we become more connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a common complaint that I hear is that people are becoming lonelier as we become more connected. An article I read theorized that by being connected to so many people, individuals have become interchangable, and therefore connections are less durable than before. We know that we are connected to others, and so, we neglect to maintain our relationships over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of me wonders if we are fated to be the same kinds of characters that pass through the world of &lt;em&gt;Sputnik Sweetheart&lt;/em&gt;. There are many people that have passed in and out of my life, and on occasion, I wonder if our paths will cross again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think that I believe in fate. How I cultivate my relationships has always been a choice, either through instinct or through premeditated intention. And after a few years of choosing to find each other again, you know who is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think of those that leave marks on my life and never return, I know that over time, I’ll find myself  thinking like the narrator at the end of the story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We’re both looking at the same moon, in the same world. We’re connected to reality by the same line. All I have to do is draw it toward me. I spread my fingers and stare at the palms of both hands, looking for bloodstains. There aren’t any. No scent of blood, no stiffness. The blood must have already, in its own, silent way, seeped inside.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laika was the first animal in space, and died from a lack of oxygen on the sixth day of her orbit. In the U.S.S.R., on that same day, Khrushchev said “Now, our first Sputnik is not lonely in its space travels.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/sputnik-painting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Art for Sputnik Sweetheart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the book Sputnik Sweetheart, and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/sputnik.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Columbus: What happens when you meet your reflection?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/10/Columbus-What-Happens-When-You-Meet-Your-Reflection" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Columbus: What happens when you meet your reflection?" /><published>2018-01-10T08:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-10T08:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/10/Columbus-What-Happens-When-You-Meet-Your-Reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/10/Columbus-What-Happens-When-You-Meet-Your-Reflection">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Columbus, and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a famous black-and-white optical illusion called Rubin’s vase, where the subject changes from a white vase to the shadows of lovers when you choose to focus on the darkness. This phenomenon, called multistable perception, involves mutually exclusive perspectives that are unified in a single image. In &lt;em&gt;Columbus&lt;/em&gt;, a place where people are seen in reflections and through mirrors, this duality can be seen in everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Columbus&lt;/em&gt; is a film written and directed by Kogonada, following Jin, a Korean man with a dying father, and Casey, a 19-year old who forewent college to take care of her mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-jin-in-rain.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jin, walking through the rain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jin, played by John Cho, reluctantly arrives in Columbus upon news of his father’s admittance to the hospital. During his first few days, he wanders aimlessly, talking on the phone to his employer overseas. As he interacts with the people around him, we learn about the way he sees his father: distant, and loved by many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He believes that his father does not need him, and draws away from him for those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-casey.png&quot; alt=&quot;Casey outside of the library&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey, played by Haley Lu Richardson, is a native to Columbus. When we first meet her, she recites facts about the surrounding architecture under her breath as she smokes. She practices a monologue about a building that is asymmetrical, but balanced- one that she repeats to Jin later on. Over time, we also learn about her relationship with her parent. She sees her mother as someone who is abandoned, loved only by her, and needs her. Casey decides not to go to college for these same reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-mirrors.png&quot; alt=&quot;Casey and Jin staring at their reflections&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lens is focused on architecture, and thus draws our attention to the environments that our characters are confined in. In Jin’s eyes, we find a stifling little town, filled with familiar sights. “You grow up around something and it feels like nothing”, he says. When he describes a psychiatric ward as “both a phyiscal bridge, and a metaphorical one”, we find that the description is his father’s, and he does not believe in his father’s idea of the healing ability of architecture. He sees it as grandiose and egocentric, as a delusion of architects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey, on the other hand, recounts a memory where she discovered the beauty in her surroundings during a difficult time in her life. She has experienced the healing ability that Jin’s father speaks of, and expresses her love to her mother in the same way- through creating a caring environment for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like water, they fill the space that they exist in. But while both of them are in Columbus, the shapes that they form are completely different. They are opposites- young and old, selfless and self-absorbed- meeting at a place and time where they are best able to learn from their differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-bridge-conversation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jin and Casey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of their relationship, when Casey gives Jin a tour of the area, he has no interest in the architecture. Instead, he asks her to tell him what she cares about- rather than the facts that she has memorized. In watching her fascination of architecture- and through it, her great capacity to love- he learns that he has a choice to care in the same ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through Jin, Casey is reminded that people make their own choices, even with the ease of a good environment. Independence is something that we all have, whether or not we choose it, and Jin acts as an example that she should make the best of her own. Casey would otherwise live a life with lingering regrets, and perhaps in the teeth of time, her ability to love would slowly be consumed. Jin explicitly reminds Casey that her mother wants what is best for her, and Casey eventually chooses to pursue a career in architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A missed connection is a tragic thing- a fact that both Jin and Casey understand in different contexts. We all have our own differences and because of this, we have a lot that we can learn from one another. And so, the two push one another to examine themselves and share, and a beautiful intimacy grows between them, like the shape of a vase between two shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-car.png&quot; alt=&quot;Casey and Jin admiring architecture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the course of the film, Jin searches for what he believes is a tower in his father’s diary. He tries to decipher the undescriptive scrawl of lines as he wanders the city, searching for a building that matches it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the film, as he shares a bag of pastries with Casey, he points at an empty space created by two brick walls. He’s unsure, but he believes that he has found the location that his father wrote about. It is not the tower that he expected, but instead, a space between two structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he settles into an apartment in Columbus to take care of his father, Casey says her goodbyes before leaving to college. Two people, from different worlds- each a reflection of the other- converged, then passed through to the other side, leaving both lives a little fuller than they were before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-tower.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jin, looking for the tower in his father's diary with Casey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Columbus, and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/columbus.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning SEO: Moving up my page rank - part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning SEO: Moving up my page rank - part 1" /><published>2018-01-07T02:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T02:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1">&lt;p&gt;Since my last post on SEO, I was able to make (relatively) significant progress with my SEO. Here, I want to talk about the &lt;strong&gt;progress&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve made, &lt;strong&gt;how I made the progress&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;next steps&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the start of my blog, I’ve been able to ramp up my viewership from &lt;strong&gt;0 users to 131 unique users&lt;/strong&gt;. These are not recurring visitors, which is what I eventually want, but they are visitors just the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see that there is a &lt;strong&gt;very high bounce rate&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll discuss this in a next steps portion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I was able to increase my page rank in searches for my full name. This means that when people look up “Elias Fong” on Google, they are more likely to see this site as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleSearchByName.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Search for Elias Fong&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I re-created the site for this URL (it was just a portfolio site in the past), the search result for this site was on the third page of results. We’ll discuss keyword optimization in a &lt;em&gt;next steps&lt;/em&gt; portion as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-i-made-the-progress&quot;&gt;How I made the progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with viewership. This part is a less impressive (to me) than my progress on page rankings, simply because I know the effort it took to reach this level of views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Google analytics, there is a nifty widget that shows the pages that people visited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-PageViews.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Page Views&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that there is a large number of views for one page, and a lot less for the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page with the most views is my post on &lt;em&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/em&gt;. At the time that I’m writing this, Call Me By Your Name is getting a lot of Oscars hype as a movie, and there is even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/callmebyyourname/&quot;&gt;Reddit community&lt;/a&gt; around the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I posted a link to the post in the reddit community, as well as on my facebook, and this is the traffic that I got from it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Channels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Sources&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is when the post went public, and the second was a private release to my friends to proofread the post. You can see that the majority of the visits come from reddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the viewership drops as the post gets older. I was unable to find other channels to publicize my post, so the only thing I did was reach out to communities that might have interest in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my &lt;strong&gt;page rank&lt;/strong&gt;, it is very important to note that the increase in rank is in searches for “Elias Fong”. I have not done any other tests yet, but ideally, I want to target certain keywords and increase my page rank on those searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is a good proof of concept for myself, and I was able to do that through &lt;em&gt;communication with Google&lt;/em&gt;. This means that I added meta tags and structured json to my page to make it easier for Google to understand what it was about, added a link to my site in all my social media to increase the number of inbound links to my site, and submitted a sitemap to Google Webmaster Tools to make it easier for Google to index my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above, I noted several things that need improvement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a high bounce rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Page rank in other keyword searches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recurring viewership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I haven’t defined it in a previous post, the bounce rate refers to the portion of people that view one page in your site, and leave without viewing any other pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the majority of my views are from my &lt;em&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/em&gt; post, it makes sense to me that viewers read the post and left right after. That being said, we may be able to improve this by adding a list of related posts to the end of each post, so that users are more likely to view another page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a lower bounce rate may help with maintaning a recurring viewership. If users feel like they like a significant amount of your content (and not just one page), they are probably more likely to come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For page rank in other keyword searches, an important thing to think about is what keywords I want to target. Are there specific people I want to see my blog? By determining who I want to find my blog, I can think about the ways they would search for what they might find on my blog, and use wording that is more relevant to those searches in my page content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally for recurring viewership, I need to develop consistency in my blog. I need to have a significant amount of content around similar topics, so that a particular user will find multiple things that they want to read on my site, as well as have a reasonable expectation that I will post more similar content. Part of this will be me, following my SEO, and the other part will be showing my new content consistently to specific channels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Since my last post on SEO, I was able to make (relatively) significant progress with my SEO. Here, I want to talk about the progress I’ve made, how I made the progress, and next steps.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Channels.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Call Me By Your Name - The Beauty of Vulnerability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/media/philosophy/2018/01/03/Call-Me-By-Your-Name-The-Beauty-of-Vulnerability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call Me By Your Name - The Beauty of Vulnerability" /><published>2018-01-03T09:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-03T09:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/media/philosophy/2018/01/03/Call%20Me%20By%20Your%20Name%20-%20The%20Beauty%20of%20Vulnerability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/media/philosophy/2018/01/03/Call-Me-By-Your-Name-The-Beauty-of-Vulnerability">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: This post is about the book Call Me By My Name, and contains many important plot points&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We rip out so much of ourselves to be cured of things faster than we should that we go bankrupt by the age of thirty and have less to offer each time we start with someone new. But to feel nothing so as not to feel anything - what a waste!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the words that Mr.Perlman- Elio’s father- chooses to tell Elio on the day that Oliver leaves for America. Elio, heartbroken and- as I would imagine- confused, returns from Rome to his home on the countryside at the end of a summer-long affair. The wounds are still fresh, and he is making sense of the monumental events that have occured over the past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When his father reveals that he knew about the secret relationship between Elio and Oliver, Elio can only expect the unfortunately common reaction to homosexuality. Instead, his father shows him a boundless tenderness, reminds him that the pain was a remnant of a beautiful experience, and advises him not to let his heart grow tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If there is pain, nurse it, and if there is a flame, don’t snuff it out, don’t be brutal with it. Withdrawal can be a terrible thing when it keeps us awake at night, and watching others forget us sooner than we’d want to be forgotten is no better”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameCouch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and Mr.Perlman on a couch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I have seen in culture today, vulnerability is thought of as only a weakness, rather than a tradeoff. “Having it all” means feeling all the good without any of the consequences, so when people are physically intimate, they try to keep an emotional distance. But how can we do things that matter, when we don’t allow anything to matter to us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by no means a condemnation of those who try to remain aloof in any kind of relationship. However, why would you deny yourself the intimacy of a connection with others? This pain is only in the heart, after all, and like all other pain, it is a reminder that you have- and can still- feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability is the consequence of allowing things and people to matter to you. In any meaningful connection, you must accept the fact that you can feel pain and pleasure from the action or inaction of others. Just like anything else that is a part of you- a limb, for example- its removal will cause you pain. Your only choice is whether or not to allow something to matter so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameCar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and his mother driving home from the train station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his later years, when Elio visits Oliver, he tells him over drinks that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You are the only person I’d like to say goodbye to when I die, because only then will this thing I call my life make any sense. And if I should hear that you died, my life as I know it, the me who is speaking with you now, will cease to exist.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a part of him that he still views in the context of Oliver in a way that is more significant than memories of a summer gone by. Something grew from those shared experiences: a part of him that influences how he acts, one that occasionally hurts from nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, he also speaks of people that came after Oliver as other monumental figures in his life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Many helped me part life into Before X and After X segments, many brought joy and sorrow, many threw my life off course, while others made no difference whatsoever, so that Oliver, who for so long had loomed like a fulcrum on the scale of life, eventually acquired successors who either eclipsed him or reduced him to an early signpost, a minor fork in the road, a small, fiery Mercury on a voyage out to Pluto and beyond. Fancy this, I might say: at the time I knew Oliver, I still hadn’t met so-and-so. Yet life without so-and-so was simply unthinkable.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because he didn’t allow his tulmultuous relationship to wound him in such a way that he did not recover, he was able to open his heart to others, while still keeping his tenderness for Oliver. And over time, the pain grew smaller and smaller, while the love stayed the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameHall.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and Oliver in the hall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read this book (twice) the month after the end of a two year long relationship- one that changed a lot about who I am, and holds a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading this, I started to see the chasm that had opened up in my life as more of a wrinkle- not in regards to the magnitude of it, but to my relationship with it. It was a reminder, now, of my ability to love and to receive love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I closed the cover on this novel for the second time, I walked away with an aspiration to keep my heart open to the world, and exemplify the kind of love that is found in “Call Me By Your Name”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Amor ch’a null’amato amar perdona. Love, which exempts no one who’s loved from loving”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameBed.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and Oliver in bed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: This post is about the book Call Me By My Name, and contains many important plot points</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/callMeByYourName.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What, Why, and How of SEO</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/02/How-do-I-increase-my-SEO" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What, Why, and How of SEO" /><published>2018-01-02T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-02T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/02/How-do-I-increase-my-SEO</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/02/How-do-I-increase-my-SEO">&lt;p&gt;What is SEO? SEO stands for “Search Engine Optimization”, and refers to the ways that people improve their visibility on search engine results (like Google Search). This is important to help people find your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to increase your visibility on search engines, you should first understand how search engines work. Sites like Google &lt;em&gt;crawl&lt;/em&gt; through the world wide web and &lt;em&gt;index&lt;/em&gt; websites, and in this process, they create lists of sites that they think are most relevant to different searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lists are ranked in both relevance and popularity, and involve many &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/search-ranking-factors&quot;&gt;different factors&lt;/a&gt; to determine the rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For popularity, you should think about the ways that people interact with your site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they looking for something?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they trying to perform an action?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And make sure that your site contains keywords that indicate how your site is related to what your user is looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, remember that while you can make flashy statements with an image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/SEO-statement.png&quot; alt=&quot;SEO statement that web crawlers can't see&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the web crawlers used by search engines can’t read it (yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, you should also think about the things that help web crawlers read your site, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alt text for images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;supplemental text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;transcripts for videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;meta tags&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sitemaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta tags are particularly important for SEO, as they also give you control over how search engines and social media interprets your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Google reads your title and description tags, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/guides/intro-structured-data&quot;&gt;structured JSON&lt;/a&gt; to generate the search results that they list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/SEO-google.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of a google search&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and Facebook uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://ogp.me/&quot;&gt;open graph tags&lt;/a&gt; (denoted by property names starting with “og:”) to build the link that they show when people share a url:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/SEO-facebook.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of a facebook share&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(this picture actually shows how I didn’t use enough tags: if I added an og:image tag, the link would show an image that would make it looke a lot prettier)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are Twitter tags (which I will not cover in this post). Twitter also uses some of the same open graph tags as Facebook, so if you prioritize facebook, you’ll get the biggest impact out of your effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of sitemaps is also easy to understand- by providing a structured list of the pages on your site, web crawlers can more easily move through the different pages and index them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/&quot;&gt;Generate a sitemap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/&quot;&gt;tell google that you own the site&lt;/a&gt;, and the indexer should do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just the tip of the iceberg- there are whole disciplines based on keyword optimization and web-crawler friendly design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will leave you with this, however: all the knowledge we’ve acquired about SEO comes from a cycle of testing and measuring results. Optimization is a process, one that requires you to gather data, analyze it, and act on it. The first step? Start using something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/analytics/&quot;&gt;google analytics&lt;/a&gt; to start understanding your users.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is SEO? SEO stands for “Search Engine Optimization”, and refers to the ways that people improve their visibility on search engine results (like Google Search). This is important to help people find your site.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/SEO.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Existential Loneliness in L’Avenir</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2017/12/31/things-to-come" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Existential Loneliness in &lt;em&gt;L'Avenir&lt;/em&gt;" /><published>2017-12-31T17:42:29-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-31T17:42:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2017/12/31/things-to-come</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2017/12/31/things-to-come">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: This post is about the movie L’Avenir (Things To Come), and contains some important plot points&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathalie, played by Isabelle Huppert, sits in the darkness inside a ferry with the white noise of the sea filling the space around her. Her children can be seen through a window, in light, outside. When her husband knocks on the glass, asking her to join them, the camera pans in to an essay she is grading, titled &lt;em&gt;“Peut-on se mettre à la place de l’autre”&lt;/em&gt;, which means: &lt;em&gt;Can we put ourselves in the place of the other&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They arrive at an island, where they visit the resting place of Chateaubriand, a great writer. Together, they observe the grave, a stone cross that faces the sea. One by one, they leave until only Heinz- the father- is left, staring into the horizon. It is then that the title “L’Avenir” appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeHorizon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Heinz looking into the horizon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the film, we see four generations of Nathalie’s family struggling in different ways, looking towards their pasts and their futures. Each moment is not without the context of the last, and the uncertainty of the next one- and in all of them lies a pervading isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow Nathalie through a divorce, the death of her mother, and the discontinuation of her published work. In regards to her essays, her publisher states, “The future seems compromised”, unknowingly speaking her mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeBus.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nathalie looking out the bus window&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loneliness that follows is most evident in her growing attention to her relationships. In an early scene, Nathalie’s mother calls in the middle of the night, and she is reasonably curt. When she visits and finds her mother confined to bed, she is ready to leave, barely looking at her while stating that she is in a rush. After Heinz leaves her, she becomes surprisingly attentive. A scene in her ex-husband’s summer home shows her desperately traveling a long distance down a beach and trudging through mud- left behind by a receded tide- just to find reception to call her mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nathalie’s mother dies, she is left with Pandora, a black cat that she never got along with. She tells Fabien, her protege, that Pandora is unbearable, and calls the cat many names during their time together. But when Pandora runs away, Nathalie spends the night wandering the edge of the woods and calling his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another phenomenon that occurs, which is best explained by Raymond Carver’s short story “Why Don’t You Dance?”. In it, a young couple dances for a man who is selling all his belongings in a yard sale. When the man dances with the girl, she says “You must be desperate or something”. And afterwards- for several weeks- she tells everyone about what happened, as if she were trying to figure out how to feel about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathalie similarly tells the people in her life self-affirming things. “Don’t worry,” she says to Fabien, “I’m taking it very well.” Earlier on in the film, you watch as she talks to her husband from behind a newspaper, or to her mother while organizing the fridge. Now, when she speaks, she looks attentively for reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeFreedom.png&quot; alt=&quot;Car ride with Fabien&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19th century philosopher Jean Paul Sartre proposed the idea that people are “condemned to be free.” Because there is no creator, there is no plan for us, and we are solely responsible for ourselves. If that is true, then we all live and die alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nathalie cries- with her cat in her otherwise empty room-  while living in a house filled with people, I can’t help but think of her exclaimation to Fabien that she has “Total Freedom”. Loneliness is typically thought of as a lack of company, but existential loneliness comes from the uncertainty of the path ahead of you. With all of her relationships changing, Nathalie is no longer certain of the role she plays, and feels lonely because of it. She searches for direction in the reactions of those around her, and only finds that she- like the rest of her world- is changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is redemption for Nathalie at the end of the film, symbolized by Fabien’s adoption of her cat- an indication of her willingness to let go. We find her among her children, and her daughter Chloe’s growing family, where she lovingly cares for her new grandchild, and as the camera pans away from her, she croons &lt;em&gt;“À la claire fontaine”&lt;/em&gt; in a room that feels warm, comforting, and filled with love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeCredits.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nathalie walking on the hills&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: This post is about the movie L’Avenir (Things To Come), and contains some important plot points</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/thingsToCome.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Designing a Personal Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing a Personal Site" /><published>2017-12-31T16:49:29-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-31T16:49:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site">&lt;p&gt;When I first started working on this site, I found the first steps of the process very difficult. How do you reduce yourself into a few words and a layout? How do you express who you are without being self-centered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are a lot of established design processes for these types of problems. The first is &lt;strong&gt;defining use cases&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply put, &lt;em&gt;how do I want my site to be used&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was mainly focused on a few cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find links to my projects/media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can see my face (somewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can read about my ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these priorities in mind, I started thinking about what I want my first impression to be, and ended up with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;current banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This came from a variety of motivations. First, I wanted to have a &lt;em&gt;picture of my face&lt;/em&gt;, in order to &lt;strong&gt;keep things personal&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/eliasInTheSun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old picture of me&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is from a &lt;em&gt;long time ago&lt;/em&gt; (don’t judge), but I really like the colors in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;explain a bit about who I am&lt;/em&gt;, I added the &lt;strong&gt;little blurb&lt;/strong&gt;, which conveniently &lt;strong&gt;links&lt;/strong&gt; to a lot of &lt;em&gt;ME things&lt;/em&gt; (like my github and instagram):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner-blurb.png&quot; alt=&quot;site banner blurb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it also has a &lt;em&gt;link to my posts&lt;/em&gt;, which are just posted below it on the home page. I chose to make it a blog because it would &lt;strong&gt;allow the site to evolve as I learn/consume new things&lt;/strong&gt; (okay, also because I wanted to blog).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The background is a picture I took on a trip in Italy that I tinted down to make the blurb easier to read. There’s a &lt;strong&gt;trend&lt;/strong&gt; in visual design centered around using more &lt;em&gt;large images&lt;/em&gt;, and its valuable to &lt;strong&gt;share a visual language with your peers&lt;/strong&gt;, in order to &lt;strong&gt;stay current&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All together, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;site banner background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That covers the first two things: having links to my projects, and a picture of my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great! Now for expressing my ideas in blog form. What are the use cases here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find the posts on google&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I plan to write about a variety of topics,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts with a certain topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because of my goal of expanding my online presence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can subscribe to my blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll write more about SEO&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;building a blog with jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; in a later post, and for now, we’ll &lt;em&gt;focus on design&lt;/em&gt;. Let’s start with the list of posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/post-link-image.png&quot; alt=&quot;post entry&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to have the list of posts on the home page, so that visitors can get straight to the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each post has an image (for visual engagement), and a title/description to show the content. I also added tags so that the user can navigate to similar posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/subscription-box.png&quot; alt=&quot;subscription box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added a subscription widget at the bottom of every page, so that I can grow a base of readers. I’m using &lt;strong&gt;mailchimp to manage the subscription&lt;/strong&gt;, which I’ll cover in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And altogether, I have a personal site that includes a blog and covers the following use cases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find links to my projects/media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can see my face (somewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can read about my ideas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts with a certain topic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can subscribe to my blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I first started working on this site, I found the first steps of the process very difficult. How do you reduce yourself into a few words and a layout? How do you express who you are without being self-centered?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/mirimar.jpg" /></entry></feed>