<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-09T23:03:06-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Elias Fong</title><subtitle>Personal site of a Elias Fong, a developer based out of Boston,  containing tutorials, reviews, and other posts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Learning SEO: Moving up my page rank - part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning SEO: Moving up my page rank - part 1" /><published>2018-01-07T02:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T02:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1">&lt;p&gt;Since my last post on SEO, I was able to make (relatively) significant progress with my SEO. Here, I want to talk about the &lt;strong&gt;progress&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve made, &lt;strong&gt;how I made the progress&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;next steps&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the start of my blog, I’ve been able to ramp up my viewership from &lt;strong&gt;0 users to 131 unique users&lt;/strong&gt;. These are not recurring visitors, which is what I eventually want, but they are visitors just the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see that there is a &lt;strong&gt;very high bounce rate&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll discuss this in the next steps portion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I was able to increase my page rank in searches for my full name. This means that when people look up “Elias Fong” on google, they are more likely to see this site as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleSearchByName.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Search for Elias Fong&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I re-created the site for this URL (it was just a portfolio site in the past), the search result for this site was on the third page of results. We’ll discuss keyword optimization in a the next steps portion as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-i-made-the-progress&quot;&gt;How I made the progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with viewership. This part is a less impressive (to me) than my progress on page rankings, simply because I know the effort it took to reach this level of views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Google analytics, there is a nifty widget that shows the pages that people visited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-PageViews.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Page Views&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that there is a large number of views for one page, and a lot less for the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page with the most views is my post on &lt;em&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/em&gt;. At the time that I’m writing this, Call Me By Your Name is getting a lot of Oscars hype as a movie, and there is even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/callmebyyourname/&quot;&gt;Reddit community&lt;/a&gt; around the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I posted a link to the post in the reddit community, as well as on my facebook, and this is the traffic that I got from it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Channels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Sources&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is when the post went public, and the second was a private release to my friends to proofreed the post. You can see that the majority of the visits come from reddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the viewership drops as the post gets older. I was unable to find other channels to publicize my post, so the only thing I did was reach out to communities that might have interest in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my &lt;strong&gt;page rank&lt;/strong&gt;, it is very important to note that the increase in rank is in searches for “Elias Fong”. I have not done any other tests yet, but ideally, I want to target certain keywords and increase my page rank on those searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is a good proof of concept for myself, and I was able to do that through &lt;em&gt;communication with Google&lt;/em&gt;. This means that I added meta tags and structured json to my page to make it easier for Google to understand what it was about, added a link to my site in all my social media to increase the number of inbound links to my site, and submitted a sitemap to Google Webmaster Tools to make it easier for Google to index my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above, I noted several things that need improvement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a high bounce rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Page rank in other keyword searches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recurring viewership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I haven’t defined it in a previous post, the bounce rate refers to the portion of people that view one page in your site, and leave without viewing any other pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the majority of my views are from my &lt;em&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/em&gt; post, it makes sense to me that viewers read the post and left right after. That being said, we may be able to improve this by adding a list of related posts to the end of each post, so that users are more likely to view another page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a lower bounce rate may help with maintaning a recurring viewership. If users feel like they like a significant amount of your content (and not just one page), they are probably more likely to come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For page rank in other keyword searches, an important thing to think about is what keywords I want to target. Are there specific people I want to see my blog? By determining who I want to find my blog, I can think about the ways they would search for what they might find on my blog, and use wording that is more relevant to those searches in my page content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally for recurring viewership, I need to develop consistency in my blog. I need to have a significant amount of content around similar topics, so that a particular user will find multiple things that they want to read on my site, as well as have a reasonable expectation that I will post more similar content. Part of this will be me, following my SEO, and the other part will be showing my new content consistently to specific channels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Since my last post on SEO, I was able to make (relatively) significant progress with my SEO. Here, I want to talk about the progress I’ve made, how I made the progress, and next steps.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Channels.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Call Me By Your Name - The Beauty of Vulnerability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/media/philosophy/2018/01/03/Call-Me-By-Your-Name-The-Beauty-of-Vulnerability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call Me By Your Name - The Beauty of Vulnerability" /><published>2018-01-03T09:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-03T09:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/media/philosophy/2018/01/03/Call%20Me%20By%20Your%20Name%20-%20The%20Beauty%20of%20Vulnerability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/media/philosophy/2018/01/03/Call-Me-By-Your-Name-The-Beauty-of-Vulnerability">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: This post is about the book Call Me By My Name, and contains many important plot points&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We rip out so much of ourselves to be cured of things faster than we should that we go bankrupt by the age of thirty and have less to offer each time we start with someone new. But to feel nothing so as not to feel anything - what a waste!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the words that Mr.Perlman- Elio’s father- chooses to tell Elio on the day that Oliver leaves for America. Elio, heartbroken and- as I would imagine- confused, returns from Rome to his home on the countryside at the end of a summer-long affair. The wounds are still fresh, and he is making sense of the monumental events that have occured over the past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When his father reveals that he knew about the secret relationship between Elio and Oliver, Elio can only expect the unfortunately common reaction to homosexuality. Instead, his father shows him a boundless tenderness, reminds him that the pain was a remnant of a beautiful experience, and advises him not to let his heart grow tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If there is pain, nurse it, and if there is a flame, don’t snuff it out, don’t be brutal with it. Withdrawal can be a terrible thing when it keeps us awake at night, and watching others forget us sooner than we’d want to be forgotten is no better”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameCouch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and Mr.Perlman on a couch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I have seen in culture today, vulnerability is thought of as only a weakness, rather than a tradeoff. “Having it all” means feeling all the good without any of the consequences, so when people are physically intimate, they try to keep an emotional distance. But how can we do things that matter, when we don’t allow anything to matter to us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by no means a condemnation of those who try to remain aloof in any kind of relationship. However, why would you deny yourself the intimacy of a connection with others? This pain is only in the heart, after all, and like all other pain, it is a reminder that you have- and can still- feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability is the consequence of allowing things and people to matter to you. In any meaningful connection, you must accept the fact that you can feel pain and pleasure from the action or inaction of others. Just like anything else that is a part of you- a limb, for example- its removal will cause you pain. Your only choice is whether or not to allow something to matter so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameCar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and his mother driving home from the train station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his later years, when Elio visits Oliver, he tells him over drinks that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You are the only person I’d like to say goodbye to when I die, because only then will this thing I call my life make any sense. And if I should hear that you died, my life as I know it, the me who is speaking with you now, will cease to exist.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a part of him that he still views in the context of Oliver in a way that is more significant than memories of a summer gone by. Something grew from those shared experiences: a part of him that influences how he acts, one that occasionally hurts from nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, he also speaks of people that came after Oliver as other monumental figures in his life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Many helped me part life into Before X and After X segments, many brought joy and sorrow, many threw my life off course, while others made no difference whatsoever, so that Oliver, who for so long had loomed like a fulcrum on the scale of life, eventually acquired successors who either eclipsed him or reduced him to an early signpost, a minor fork in the road, a small, fiery Mercury on a voyage out to Pluto and beyond. Fancy this, I might say: at the time I knew Oliver, I still hadn’t met so-and-so. Yet life without so-and-so was simply unthinkable.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because he didn’t allow his tulmultuous relationship to wound him in such a way that he did not recover, he was able to open his heart to others, while still keeping his tenderness for Oliver. And over time, the pain grew smaller and smaller, while the love stayed the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameHall.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and Oliver in the hall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read this book (twice) the month after the end of a two year long relationship- one that changed a lot about who I am, and holds a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading this, I started to see the chasm that had opened up in my life as more of a wrinkle- not in regards to the magnitude of it, but to my relationship with it. It was a reminder, now, of my ability to love and to receive love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I closed the cover on this novel for the second time, I walked away with an aspiration to keep my heart open to the world, and exemplify the kind of love that is found in “Call Me By Your Name”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Amor ch’a null’amato amar perdona. Love, which exempts no one who’s loved from loving”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/callMeByYourNameBed.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elio and Oliver in bed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: This post is about the book Call Me By My Name, and contains many important plot points</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/callMeByYourName.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What, Why, and How of SEO</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/02/How-do-I-increase-my-SEO" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What, Why, and How of SEO" /><published>2018-01-02T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-02T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/02/How-do-I-increase-my-SEO</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/02/How-do-I-increase-my-SEO">&lt;p&gt;What is SEO? SEO stands for “Search Engine Optimization”, and refers to the ways that people improve their visibility on search engine results (like Google Search). This is important for help people find your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to increase your visibility on search engines, you should first understand how search engines work. Sites like Google &lt;em&gt;crawl&lt;/em&gt; through the world wide web and &lt;em&gt;index&lt;/em&gt; websites, and in this process, they create lists of sites that they think are most relevant to different searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lists are ranked in both relevance and popularity, and involve many &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/search-ranking-factors&quot;&gt;different factors&lt;/a&gt; to determine the rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For popularity, you should think about the ways that people interact with your site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they looking for something?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they trying to perform an action?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And make sure that your site contains keywords that indicate how your site is related to what your user is looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, remember that while you can make flashy statements with an image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/SEO-statement.png&quot; alt=&quot;SEO statement that web crawlers can't see&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the web crawlers used by search engines can’t read it (yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, you should also think about the things that help web crawlers read your site, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alt text for images&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;supplemental text&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;transcripts for videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;meta tags&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sitemaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta tags are particularly important for SEO, as they also give you control over how search engines and social media interprets your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Google reads your title and description tags, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/guides/intro-structured-data&quot;&gt;structured JSON&lt;/a&gt; to generate the search results that they list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/SEO-google.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of a google search&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and Facebook uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://ogp.me/&quot;&gt;open graph tags&lt;/a&gt; (denoted by property names starting with “og:”) to build the link that they show when people share a url:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/SEO-facebook.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of a facebook share&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(this picture actually shows how I didn’t use enough tags: if I added an og:image tag, the link would show an image that would make it looke a lot prettier)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are Twitter tags (which I will not cover in this post). Twitter also uses some of the same open graph tags as Facebook, so if you prioritize facebook, you’ll get the biggest impact out of your effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of sitemaps is also easy to understand- by providing a structured list of the pages on your site, web crawlers can more easily move through the different pages and index them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/&quot;&gt;Generate a sitemap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/&quot;&gt;tell google that you own the site&lt;/a&gt;, and the indexer should do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just the tip of the iceberg- there are whole disciplines based on keyword optimization and web-crawler friendly design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will leave you with this, however: all the knowledge we’ve acquired about SEO comes from a cycle of testing and measuring results. Optimization is a process, one that requires you to gather data, analyze it, and act on it. The first step? Start using something like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/analytics/&quot;&gt;google analytics&lt;/a&gt; to start understanding your users.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is SEO? SEO stands for “Search Engine Optimization”, and refers to the ways that people improve their visibility on search engine results (like Google Search). This is important for help people find your site.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/SEO.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Existential Loneliness in L’Avenir</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2017/12/31/things-to-come" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Existential Loneliness in &lt;em&gt;L'Avenir&lt;/em&gt;" /><published>2017-12-31T17:42:29-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-31T17:42:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2017/12/31/things-to-come</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2017/12/31/things-to-come">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: This post is about the movie L’Avenir (Things To Come), and contains some important plot points&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathalie, played by Isabelle Huppert, sits in the darkness inside a ferry with the white noise of the sea filling the space around her. Her children can be seen through a window, in light, outside. When her husband knocks on the glass, asking her to join them, the camera pans in to an essay she is grading, titled &lt;em&gt;“Peut-on se mettre à la place de l’autre”&lt;/em&gt;, which means: &lt;em&gt;Can we put ourselves in the place of the other&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They arrive at an island, where they visit the resting place of Chateaubriand, a great writer. Together, they observe the grave, a stone cross that faces the sea. One by one, they leave until only Heinz- the father- is left, staring into the horizon. It is then that the title “L’Avenir” appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeHorizon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Heinz looking into the horizon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the film, we see four generations of Nathalie’s family struggling in different ways, looking towards their pasts and their futures. Each moment is not without the context of the last, and the uncertainty of the next one- and in all of them lies a pervading isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow Nathalie through a divorce, the death of her mother, and the discontinuation of her published work. In regards to her essays, her publisher states, “The future seems compromised”, unknowingly speaking her mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeBus.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nathalie looking out the bus window&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loneliness that follows is most evident in her growing attention to her relationships. In an early scene, Nathalie’s mother calls in the middle of the night, and she is reasonably curt. When she visits and finds her mother confined to bed, she is ready to leave, barely looking at her while stating that she is in a rush. After Heinz leaves her, she becomes surprisingly attentive. A scene in her ex-husband’s summer home shows her desperately traveling a long distance down a beach and trudging through mud- left behind by a receded tide- just to find reception to call her mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nathalie’s mother dies, she is left with Pandora, a black cat that she never got along with. She tells Fabien, her protege, that Pandora is unbearable, and calls the cat many names during their time together. But when Pandora runs away, Nathalie spends the night wandering the edge of the woods and calling his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another phenomenon that occurs, which is best explained by Raymond Carver’s short story “Why Don’t You Dance?”. In it, a young couple dances for a man who is selling all his belongings in a yard sale. When the man dances with the girl, she says “You must be desperate or something”. And afterwards- for several weeks- she tells everyone about what happened, as if she were trying to figure out how to feel about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathalie similarly tells the people in her life self-affirming things. “Don’t worry,” she says to Fabien, “I’m taking it very well.” Earlier on in the film, you watch as she talks to her husband from behind a newspaper, or to her mother while organizing the fridge. Now, when she speaks, she looks attentively for reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeFreedom.png&quot; alt=&quot;Car ride with Fabien&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19th century philosopher Jean Paul Sartre proposed the idea that people are “condemned to be free.” Because there is no creator, there is no plan for us, and we are solely responsible for ourselves. If that is true, then we all live and die alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nathalie cries- with her cat in her otherwise empty room-  while living in a house filled with people, I can’t help but think of her exclaimation to Fabien that she has “Total Freedom”. Loneliness is typically thought of as a lack of company, but existential loneliness comes from the uncertainty of the path ahead of you. With all of her relationships changing, Nathalie is no longer certain of the role she plays, and feels lonely because of it. She searches for direction in the reactions of those around her, and only finds that she- like the rest of her world- is changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is redemption for Nathalie at the end of the film, symbolized by Fabien’s adoption of her cat- an indication of her willingness to let go. We find her among her children, and her daughter Chloe’s growing family, where she lovingly cares for her new grandchild, and as the camera pans away from her, she croons &lt;em&gt;“À la claire fontaine”&lt;/em&gt; in a room that feels warm, comforting, and filled with love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thingsToComeCredits.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nathalie walking on the hills&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: This post is about the movie L’Avenir (Things To Come), and contains some important plot points</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/thingsToCome.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Designing a Personal Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing a Personal Site" /><published>2017-12-31T16:49:29-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-31T16:49:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site">&lt;p&gt;When I first started working on this site, I found the first steps of the process very difficult. How do you reduce yourself into a few words and a layout? How do you express who you are without being self-centered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are a lot of established design processes for these types of problems. The first is &lt;strong&gt;defining use cases&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply put, &lt;em&gt;how do I want my site to be used&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was mainly focused on a few cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find links to my projects/media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can see my face (somewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can read about my ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these priorities in mind, I started thinking about what I want my first impression to be, and ended up with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;current banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This came from a variety of motivations. First, I wanted to have a &lt;em&gt;picture of my face&lt;/em&gt;, in order to &lt;strong&gt;keep things personal&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/eliasInTheSun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old picture of me&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is from a &lt;em&gt;long time ago&lt;/em&gt; (don’t judge), but I really like the colors in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;explain a bit about who I am&lt;/em&gt;, I added the &lt;strong&gt;little blurb&lt;/strong&gt;, which conveniently &lt;strong&gt;links&lt;/strong&gt; to a lot of &lt;em&gt;ME things&lt;/em&gt; (like my github and instagram):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner-blurb.png&quot; alt=&quot;site banner blurb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it also has a &lt;em&gt;link to my posts&lt;/em&gt;, which are just posted below it on the home page. I chose to make it a blog because it would &lt;strong&gt;allow the site to evolve as I learn/consume new things&lt;/strong&gt; (okay, also because I wanted to blog).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The background is a picture I took on a trip in Italy that I tinted down to make the blurb easier to read. There’s a &lt;strong&gt;trend&lt;/strong&gt; in visual design centered around using more &lt;em&gt;large images&lt;/em&gt;, and its valuable to &lt;strong&gt;share a visual language with your peers&lt;/strong&gt;, in order to &lt;strong&gt;stay current&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All together, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;site banner background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That covers the first two things: having links to my projects, and a picture of my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great! Now for expressing my ideas in blog form. What are the use cases here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find the posts on google&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I plan to write about a variety of topics,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts with a certain topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because of my goal of expanding my online presence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can subscribe to my blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll write more about SEO&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;building a blog with jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; in a later post, and for now, we’ll &lt;em&gt;focus on design&lt;/em&gt;. Let’s start with the list of posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/post-link-image.png&quot; alt=&quot;post entry&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to have the list of posts on the home page, so that visitors can get straight to the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each post has an image (for visual engagement), and a title/description to show the content. I also added tags so that the user can navigate to similar posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/subscription-box.png&quot; alt=&quot;subscription box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added a subscription widget at the bottom of every page, so that I can grow a base of readers. I’m using &lt;strong&gt;mailchimp to manage the subscription&lt;/strong&gt;, which I’ll cover in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And altogether, I have a personal site that includes a blog and covers the following use cases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find links to my projects/media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can see my face (somewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can read about my ideas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts with a certain topic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can subscribe to my blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I first started working on this site, I found the first steps of the process very difficult. How do you reduce yourself into a few words and a layout? How do you express who you are without being self-centered?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/mirimar.jpg" /></entry></feed>