<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-25T08:44:57-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Elias Fong</title><subtitle>Personal site of a Elias Fong, a developer based out of Boston,  containing tutorials, reviews, and other posts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Unsane: Room for Conspiracy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/03/24/Unsane" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unsane: Room for Conspiracy" /><published>2018-03-24T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-24T14:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/03/24/Unsane</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/03/24/Unsane">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Unsane (2018), and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think of the word insane, I imagine a sterile psych ward and a patient in white spotted gown, with only their long, frazzled hair visible from behind. You’d hear their quiet mumbling from the entrance of the room, accompanied by an occasional twitch. When you take a few steps forward, the mumbling would become louder, and you’d begin to recognize them as the words of a babbled theory, maybe about the people out to get them, or a secret no one knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/unsane_first_day.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sawyer walking into the patient residence&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Unsane, we follow Sawyer, a woman who might have been involuntarily committed to a psych ward as she tries to convince her caretakers that she is imprisioned by her stalker. Sawyer’s captivity begins when she accidentally signs a form that allows them to admit her to the facility for 24 hours. On the first night, she encounters a caretaker who looks exactly like the man who stalked her, and strikes him in the face out of shock. After the rest of the staff wrestles her down and sedates her, the attending physician of the facility hears about the incident, and uses it to justify the extension of her stay from a day to a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/unsane_friend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sawyer and her friend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the other patients explains to Sawyer that erroneous admittance to the facility occurs frequently, mainly so that these companies can harvest insurance money. He explains that they have a quota- just like everyone else- and that hospitals are, first and foremost, a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is able to contact her mother with his phone, and her mother attempts to free her, but is entangled in a web of bureaucracy. The hospital tells her that there is no better place for Sawyer, and the lawyers tell her that there is nothing they can do until the end of the seven days. Even the police tell her mother that there is nothing she can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/unsane_body.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dead body found by a runner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days, Sawyer’s stalker drugs her, kills her mother, and isolates her in a padded room. He confesses his love and asks her to live with her in the woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is never made clear whether Sawyer is truly insane, or if she was ever in the facility in the first place. But as unreliable as she is, her conspiracy is somehow perfectly believable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/unsane_restrained.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sawyer restrained to her bed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When does a conspiracy become belivable? When do babbeled theories from the mouth of a psych patient appear plausible? All it requires is just enough room for doubt. And in the world of Unsane (a world much like our own), there is plenty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a place where male bosses attempt to lure women into compromising situations with the glittering lure of a successful career. A place where hospitals are motivated by money and imprision people to harvest their insurance. Where a stalker objectifies Sawyer enough to believe that love is capturing someone in an empty blue room and forcing them to bend to your will. Anything other than what he expects is written off as insanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things are easy to believe here, even when we are shown that the narrator is delusional, because they are plausible. They are stories that we’ve scrolled past on facebook, or tales told by friends of friends- just out of reach so that we are not involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is room- just enough room- to believe that we live in the same reality of the Unsane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/unsane_stalker.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sawyer's Stalker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Unsane (2018), and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/unsane.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoroughbreds: Systemic Socialization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/03/11/Thoroughbreds" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoroughbreds: Systemic Socialization" /><published>2018-03-11T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-11T14:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/03/11/Thoroughbreds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/03/11/Thoroughbreds">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Thoroughbreds (2018), and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Lily’s world, someone always picks up the trash: whether its a bag of chips on the kitchen table, or the consequences of murder. She lives in a $17.5 million &lt;a href=&quot;http://cohasset.wickedlocal.com/news/20170608/roy-estate-in-cohasset-is-back-on-market&quot;&gt;Georgian Revival style home&lt;/a&gt; with 45 rooms, a tennis court, and a private beach. Expensive antiques and artistic busts line each wall: installations that are so familiar that only the local drug dealer, played by Anton Yelchin, seems to appreciate them. But while the lavishness of Lily’s lifestyle is lost on her, make no mistake- this world is her’s, and all the characters only inhabit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One character in particular exists in her world the way an itch lives on a person’s skin- uncomfortably and unwelcomed. Mark, her stepfather, seems to oppose her at every turn, standing between her and the way she expects the world to be. When she is expelled from boarding school, he enrolls her in a school for troubled girls. When her friend Amanda visits, he attempts to send her home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, naturally, she decides to murder him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thoroughbreds-tan.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lily next to the tanning bed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago, on a sunny afternoon in Cambridge, I was playing basketball with one of my friends, when I witnessed a child trip and fall a few feet from the basket. The fist-sized basketball he was holding rolled away from him, and I jogged over to retrieve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I walked back to return it, I watched as the father kneeled beside the crying child, who reached out to him with open arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re okay,” he said, “Now pick yourself up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The child continued crying and reaching out to his father, who only responded by saying, “Come on, you can do it”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the kid rolled over and stood. The father told him that he did a good job, and then gave him a hug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That moment has always stood out to me as a model of parenting, and as a representation of real love. It makes me think of the consequences of the alternative, when parents fuss over a falling child. Will the child begin to equate crying with a solution? Will they begin to expect the world to swoop in and pick them up when they fall?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thoroughbreds-entry.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walking into Lily's Mansion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine that these are the beginnings of the kind of entitlement that Thoroughbreds’ writer and director, Cory Finley, finds when he writes about the suburbs of Conneticut. The world of Thoroughbreds is populated with super rich kids who have everything, and believe that they deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we find Amanda, a black sheep in the community, who seems to be disillusioned by all of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first meet her, Amanda faces her horse with a knife in hand. Her face is stone-cold, emotionless. We later find that she killed her horse in a seemingly brutal fashion and has been tied up in a conviction for animal cruelty. Everyone around her tries to explain her capacity for violence, through rumor and diagnosis, but only Lily eventually learns the truth. Her horse was ill, and she put it out of its misery. She tried to make it as painless as possible, but it became violent after a series of miscalculations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is the furthest from peers, and instead of feeling entitled, she is simply apathetic. Like everyone else in her community, all of Amanda’s needs are fulfilled, however, she is different in that she wants nothing. The expression on her face seems to always say &lt;em&gt;what’s the point?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The influence of Amanda’s world on her worldview is much more subtle. Instead of feeling the need to make her world conform to her, she feels like she is conditioned to conform to her world. Every emotion is practiced, and even when she cries, she does it for someone else. It does not appear to make her feel good, to conform, either. It simply seems like she feels like that is her role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thoroughbreds-amanda.png&quot; alt=&quot;Amanda hiding with a knife&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together, Lily and Amanda stare at the ceiling toward the churning sound of Mark on a rowing machine as Lily plots his murder, and Amanda follows along. Lily believes that Mark is only on the machine to drive her crazy, while Amanda only wants to do whatever it is that a good friend would do. They are both taught by society to expect specific outcomes and act in specific ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end, both Lily and Amanda take a step outside of their own worlds. Lily mourns for the loss of a friend, the first time she is sad about something outside of her own feelings, even though she is solely responsible for her imprisionment. Amanda finds a freedom in the confines of the psychatric ward she is transferred to, genuinely smiling for the first time when she is alone, staring at an old picture of her and Lily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Amanda writes to Lily, she describes a dream in which horses run free over the ruins of society, not knowing who they are and what they are worth. Finally free because they do not know what they are meant to be. And in their shared act of rebellion, the two girls discover a new part of themselves in one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/thoroughbreds-couch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lily and Amanda on the couch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Thoroughbreds (2018), and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/thoroughbreds.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plato’s Epistemology and Learning from Beauty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/philosophy/2018/02/28/Platos-epistemology-and-learning-from-beauty.markdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plato's Epistemology and Learning from Beauty" /><published>2018-02-28T13:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-28T13:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/philosophy/2018/02/28/Platos-epistemology-and-learning-from-beauty.markdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/philosophy/2018/02/28/Platos-epistemology-and-learning-from-beauty.markdown">&lt;p&gt;Why do we enjoy beauty? And what makes beautiful qualities beautiful? When I look at the painting above- Monet’s &lt;em&gt;Soleil Levant&lt;/em&gt;- I justify that the beauty here is in the stark contrast of color and the gentleness of the brush strokes. His impression of the sunrise feels honest, and I can empathize with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my explanation does not quite answer why the painting is beautiful. My answer is subjective- I am only saying that the painting is beautiful because of the things I find beautiful about it. Contrast, color, gentleness and honesty- those are the things that I see in the painting, and those are the true subjects of my admiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is there that Plato’s question begins: what makes qualities that we find beautiful, beautiful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/damien-hirst-myth-explored-explained-exploded.png&quot; alt=&quot;Damien Hirst's &amp;quot;Myth Explored, Explained, Exploded&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His epistemological theory (theory of knowledge) of anamnesis is this: when we are born, our souls carry all knowledge. But when our soul is placed into our bodies, we lose that knowledge. In &lt;em&gt;Meno&lt;/em&gt;, he suggests that the soul is immortal and repeatedly incarnated, but the trauma of birth causes us to forget the things that we’ve always known. Without that trauma, we would carry all the knowledge from our past lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;em&gt;Theory of Forms&lt;/em&gt;, Plato suggests that there are ideas that exist independently of those who have those ideas. Forms are immutable truths that are the objective essence of what we refer to subjectively. Think of “Forms” as short hand for “true form”- they represent the aspects of something that make it what it is (what makes all cats, cats?). In the example of Beauty (with a capital &lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; as one of the &lt;em&gt;Forms&lt;/em&gt;), the best way that I can perceive of it is as the shared quality of all art that draws any observer to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Phaedo&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;On The Soul&lt;/em&gt;, he combines this idea of Forms with his idea of anamnesis, and states that one way of learning after birth is to study the Forms. By studying these objective truths, we can regain the knowledge that we’ve always known- and have forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under this theory, the things that I saw in Monet’s painting- contrast, color, gentleness, and honesty- are all values that enrich my life in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/degas-rehearsal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Degas's &amp;quot;Rehearsal&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I appreciate this contemplation on the soul and objective truths, I am more interested in the ways that I can apply this concept to my life. I imagine that Plato drew these grand ideas from simple concepts that he encountered in day-to-day life. When I think about the way Plato describes the soul- the knowledge it carries, and its reincarnation from past lives- it appears to closely resemble human instinct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instincts are inborn behaviors that we perform without learning, and are likely genetic. Some of our reactions- such as those to pain and pleasure- are instinctual, and represent a long lineage of familiar reaction to the same stimulus. Although a lot of appreciation is learned, I believe my visceral reactions toward beautiful things come from my instinct- a part of myself that I have not entirely rationalized or understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of centuries, some aspects of the world have always remained rewarding to those who pursue them. And their feelings are the same as what I feel when I look at these paintings. Honesty is rewarding because it improves communication. Contrast teaches us the value of differences. The value of gentleness is in humility and courtesy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine my parents, my grandparents, and all my ancestors, standing in a line that stretches into the horizon. They pass on a whispered secret, from one parent to the next, waiting for me to understand their wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, in the present, I write as I try to understand the Form of Beauty. Maybe by following my feelings toward beautiful things, I can begin to learn more about myself, my world, and my place within it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/damien-hirst-tetrahydrocannabinol-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Damien Hirst, &amp;quot;Tetrahyrocannabinol-6&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Why do we enjoy beauty? And what makes beautiful qualities beautiful? When I look at the painting above- Monet’s Soleil Levant- I justify that the beauty here is in the stark contrast of color and the gentleness of the brush strokes. His impression of the sunrise feels honest, and I can empathize with it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/plato_claude_monet_impression_soleil_levant.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Annihilation: Change and the concept of the self</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/02/22/Annihilation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Annihilation: Change and the concept of the self" /><published>2018-02-22T13:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-22T13:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/02/22/Annihilation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/02/22/Annihilation">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Annihilation, and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A meteor strikes a solitary lighthouse on a quiet beach. A veil of colorful light appears, surrounding the explosion. The land begins to distort from the impact. This is the anomaly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lena, played by Natalie Portman, sits in confinement, wearing white scrubs. Through a pane of glass, a line of scientists watch as she is interrogated. 
“Can you describe its form?”
“Was it carbon based?”
“Its destroying everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Its not destroying,” she says, “its making something new.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/annihilation-lena-interrogation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lena being Interrogated&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through their exchanges, it is apparent that the scientists are fearful of the anomaly caused by the meteor. They ask if she felt afraid, and ask what the mutated creatures that live inside are like. With each answer, they are continually surprised. “Sometimes, it was very beautiful,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we follow Lena inside the anomaly, we learn that the environment is one in which all things are continually merging, where pieces of DNA fly from a plant to a person, and a scream can pass from the throat of a soldier to the mouth of a bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a place characterized by change, where the boundaries between the self and the environment are blurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/annihilation-fauna.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mutated Duplicate Deer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the self? The dictionary defines it as “a person’s essential being that distinguishes them from others”. The thesaurus likens it to the ego, persona, identity, character, and spirit. And philosophers see it as an activity, delusion, a narrative, and a bundle of perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The philosophy found in Annihilation is in favor of the concept of the self as a bundle of perceptions, but also argues that in order to change from one state to another, we must destroy our past selves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/annihilation-team.png&quot; alt=&quot;Exploration Team&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cass, one of the scientists on the expedition, describes their group as “damaged goods”. Each one of them has been struck by some difficulty or tragedy that has consumed their sense of self- like the lighthouse at the center of the anomaly. Their journeys through the anomaly reflect their feelings in relation to their struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cass, who had a death in her family, states that part of her died along with them. This demonstrates the ways in which she defines herself by others. When a creature in the anomaly takes her, it also takes her voice, which it uses to impersonate her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josie is described as someone who resorted to self-harm to feel something- and she disappears in the anomaly with leaves growing from her scarred wrists. She resigns herself in the endless pursuit of change for the sake of change, and loses her sense of self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr.Ventress enters the anomaly expecting to die within it, wanting only to seek the truth behind it. And in seeking truth for the sake of truth, she looses her mind in an endless search, one that becomes more and more abstract, until she also disappears into the anomaly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Lena is different from them all. She is the only one who wants to come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/annihilation-husband.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lena's Husband, quarantined&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value of this desire is illustrated thoughout the movie, but particularly in the last part of the movie, where she finds a mirror image of herself. During this scene, she fights, understands, then destroys this entity, which represents her, and was created from a drop of her blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One cell becomes two, two becomes four, four becomes eight, and so on” Lena lectures. All life comes from the same humble beginnings. From bacteria to flora to humanity, each is a consitiuent of its ever-changing parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these parts live and die without our knowledge. Every ten years, your body is nearly completely replaced with new cells. But in lieu of that, would you say that you are no longer yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any change of the self, a past self is buried and replaced. As Lena states, this is not destruction- it is creation. Every little mutation that you undergo changes and replaces parts of you, and one must let go of the concepts of before and after to embrace the full embodiment of the self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/annihilation-love.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lena and her husband&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Annihilation, and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/annihilation.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Bird Revelation and The Capitalism Machine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/society/media/philosophy/2018/02/08/The-Bird-Revelation-And-The-Capitalism-Machine" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bird Revelation and The Capitalism Machine" /><published>2018-02-08T05:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-08T05:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/society/media/philosophy/2018/02/08/The-Bird-Revelation-And-The-Capitalism-Machine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/society/media/philosophy/2018/02/08/The-Bird-Revelation-And-The-Capitalism-Machine">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: This post describes one of the stories told in Dave Chappelle’s The Bird Revelation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smoke rises from a cigarette, pinched between two fingers. The stage is smaller than the others in his past three specials: it’s an intimate space where the audience sits at an arm’s length. Dave Chappelle hunches over his stool with a white book in his hand, waving it around like a preacher does with a bible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something different here, and you wonder if its the dark curtain or the red lighting. Maybe its the smoke that swirls over his face. But when he begins to speak, you realize that it’s none of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chappelle is vulnerable- for the first time that I can remember- and as he speaks, the audience is not sure whether to laugh or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/chappelle-wide-shot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chappelle on his pulpit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chappelle begins by saying that this is the story about why he left the Chappelle Show in 2005. “I can tell you why, but I can’t say it directly,” he says, and an assistant from the back of the room comes forward with a white-covered book titled “Pimp”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pimp was written in the 60’s by a man named Robert Beck, otherwise known as Iceberg Slim. He was a pimp from the age of 18 until the age of 42, who moved out to Los Angeles after spending some time in jail and decided to write about his experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He breaks down some of the coldest capitalist concepts,” Chappelle claims as he waves the book. Then, he asks the audience if they know what the phrase &lt;em&gt;mileage on a ho&lt;/em&gt; means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A knowing chuckle passes through the audience. I remember laughing myself. But then Chappelle begins to explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mileage on a ho refers to the number of times a pimp thinks that a prostitute can have sex for. Chappelle further explains that this means that a pimp understands that &lt;em&gt;there is a finite amount of bad things that a person can do before they lose it&lt;/em&gt;. My eyes open wide as I realize that he is trying to speak seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then describes another part of the book, where Iceberg Slim asks a mentor for advice on controling a woman who is too headstrong. The mentor tells him to beat her with a hanger, give her some pills, and run her a bath- and &lt;em&gt;“she’ll be so grateful you fixed her that she’ll forget you were the motherfucker that beat her in the first place”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iceberg Slim eventually does this to a woman who is planning to stop working for him by making her believe that she killed someone- and that he was helping protect her. She was a prostitute that was at the end of her mileage, and he was able to keep her working for six more months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s a cold game,” Chappelle says, “Thats the motherfucking capitalist manifesto. And that’s why I went to South Africa.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/chappelle-with-pimp-book.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chappelle with the book, Pimp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern day captalism has several primary characteristics: private property, capital accumulation, wage labor, voluntary exchange, a price system, and competitive markets. Capitalism is an economic system, meaning that it is a system that allocates resources within a society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are fantastic things. Think about the computer that you own, alone, that no one else can access without your permission. Think about the money you have in your bank- instead of a storage unit full of little trinkets to barter. Think about the fact that you don’t need to decide how much your lunch costs every time you buy it. There’s a little machine that does all of these things for us, and it’s called capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are acknowledged systemic weaknesses in a capitalistic society. The first one is called a &lt;em&gt;market failure&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;externality&lt;/em&gt;. This is when the system fails to account for certain aspects of a product, and allows overproduction or underproduction of that product. For example, if your neighbor plays music too loudly at night, you experience a negative externality, because you are suffering for something that you do not get to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second one is anti-competitive practices. Examples of this are monopolies (where one company controls an entire market), price fixing (where companies collude to set prices), and exclusive dealing (where people only purchase from certain people to reduce competition).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third, the one we will focus on, is the exploitation of the working class by a minority of capitalists who control all the means of production and distribution. In other words, the unfair distribution of wealth and as a result, social inequality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a system, where a small minority of people control a large majority of the wealth, and therefore hold most of the power. In this situation, capital accumulation is unbalanced in such a way that the system no longer serves a large majority of the people who are a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while this is all happening, this system only incentivizes the accumulation of capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what Chappelle sees: a system with no morals. This system blindly incentivies value, and as a result, we have people like Iceberg Slim, using any method possible to make money and control others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system was not made to incentivize morality. We have laws that are meant to combat illicit behavior, and government enforced taxes used to reduce externalities, but in the end, we have a system that is made for the exchange of goods, rather than for creating a caring society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is all intentional- even in our ideas of a perfect society, there are differences in values between every person. The religious among us are more concerned about sin, the hedonistic more are concerned about consumption, and there are many others who hold different values. There cannot be an economic system that enforces one of these beliefs over the other if we choose to keep our freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is not to say that the system is exactly what it needs to be. It is far from it. But I think this means that we need to pay closer attention to the culture we are creating within the framework of capitalism. If we are to uphold the importance of values over capital, we must find ways to make that the norm, whether it is changes to the system, or to ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/chappelle-iceberg-slim.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iceberg Slim&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: This post describes one of the stories told in Dave Chappelle’s The Bird Revelation</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/chappelle.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Origin Stories and How They Shape Us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/society/philosophy/2018/01/27/Origin-Stories-And-How-They-Shape-Us" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origin Stories and How They Shape Us" /><published>2018-01-27T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-27T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/society/philosophy/2018/01/27/Origin-Stories-And-How-They-Shape-Us</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/society/philosophy/2018/01/27/Origin-Stories-And-How-They-Shape-Us">&lt;p&gt;What are the events that are most significant in your life? If you were to name one, what would it be? Take a second, and think of one. I want you to keep it in the back of your mind as we consider the effects of a shared story that is exceptionally significant to humanity: the story of Adam and Eve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve are fabled to be the progenitors of humanity, created from dust and bone by God. As the story goes, God created man- Adam- in his own image to look over the Earth and its creatures, and woman- Eve- to be his helper. The two live in the garden of Eden, a paradise where there is no violence. They are allowed to eat from any tree except one- the tree of the knowledge of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You are free to eat from any tree in the garden; but you must not eat from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, for when you eat from it you will certainly die.”&lt;/em&gt; - Genesis 2:16-17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fall of mankind occurs when a serpent tempts Eve to eat from the tree. She eats some of it, then gives the rest to Adam, who also eats it. And it is then that their eyes are opened. They begin to feel shame for their nakedness, and are banished from the garden of Eden for their sin. God curses them both, saying to Eve:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I will make your pains in childbearing very severe
with painful labor you will give birth to children.
&lt;strong&gt;your desire will be for your husband,
and he will rule over you.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/em&gt; - Genesis 3:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to Adam:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Cursed is the ground because of you;
&lt;strong&gt;through painful toil you will eat food from it
all the days of your life.&lt;/strong&gt;
It will produce thorns and thistles for you,
and you will eat the plants of the field.
By the sweat of your brow
you will eat your food
until you return to the ground,
since from it you were taken;
for dust you are
and &lt;strong&gt;to dust you will return.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/em&gt; - Genesis 3:17-19&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/the-judgement-of-adam-and-eve-by-god.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bernward Doors, The Judgement of Adam and Eve by God&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Rise and Fall of Adam and Eve&lt;/em&gt;, Stephen Greenblatt explores this story- why it has lasted through the test of time, and how its interpretation has changed over centuries. He argues that the story captures the struggles of humanity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The story of Adam and Eve speaks to all of us. It addresses who we are, where we came from, why we love and why we suffer… It capures the strange way our species treats work, sex, and death- features of existence that we share with every other animal- as objects of speculation, as if they were contingent on something we have done, as if it could all have been otherwise.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sentiments in the last sentence are particularly interesting- and lightly touches on the awareness of mortality that is unique to humanity. Death has largely been regarded as a senseless violence that is inflicted upon us- one in which we have no control or involvement. In many religions, stories revolve around the explanation of this imminent event. In the story of Adam and Eve, we are the direct cause of our own demise. But the reason we tell all these stories is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Something happened at the beginning of time- some history of decision, action, and reaction- that led to the way we are, and if we want to understand the way we are, it is important to remember and retell this story.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/Francois-Lemoyne-Adam-and-Eve.png&quot; alt=&quot;Francois Lemoyne, Adam and Eve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want you to think about the significant event that you recalled at the beginning of this post. If it was a negative event, why do you think it had such an impact on your life? Was it a situation where you felt like you were in control? Or felt like you could have had control, but didn’t? Is it an event that you completely understand? Or is there room for speculation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is common for people to seek closure in the aftermath of negative events. Without explanation, the things that make us feel bad seem senseless and meaningless, which leads to an endless echo of “why?”. Why did this happen to me? And what could I have done about it? How does this significant event have meaning in my life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Humans seem to be the only animals on earth that ask themselves how they came to be and why they are the way they are. We could represent this uniqueness as an achievement, a mark of distinction, as perhaps it is. But it would be easy enough to seize upon it instead as a sign that we are lost- disoriented, uncomfortable in our own skin, in need of an explanation.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In significant events in general, a specific context is created around your sense of self. It is easy to think of yourself in relation to the things that you experience, and the things that have happened to you. We try to understand ourselves by understanding the events in our past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to focus on this context that we create for ourselves. It holds a great power- the power to shape our decisions. However, just like any tool, it has strengths, weaknesses, and sometimes unintended side effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Adam and Eve, the great struggle and purpose of mankind is established. This story, largely symbolic, was originally regarded as allegorical in its earlier interpretations. However, over time, as people scrutinized it and adapted it to their own uses in their lives, the interpretation of it changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly, Augustine, a theologian who lived around 370 CE, began to push for a literal interpretation of the story of Adam and Eve, which became largely popular. This acceptance of the literal interpretation was incentivized by many of the misogynistic philosophies of the time, which benefitted from the literal interpretation of God’s curse on women that men would rule over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the origin of these shared beliefs was forgotten, and was accepted as fact by many religious communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1945, alternative stories written around Adam and Eve were found in Luxor. These stories, written shortly after the first written versions of Adam and Eve, described the fall in a different light. “The Apocalypse of Adam” is a sequel to Adam and Eve, written in first person, where Adam writes about the events in the garden of Eden. It offers an alternate perspective, where women are not the ones who led to the fall of mankind, but rather the benefactors of all knowledge. “We were higher than the god who had created us”, he writes, describing their state after receiving knowledge from the tree of good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point I want to make here is that these stories have provided comfort and motivation toward moral aspirations for centuries, but its meaning is subject to interpretation. And these interpretations have made historical impacts in both harmful and beneficial ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also trying to draw a clear parallel to our personal origin stories, and the importance of how we choose to understand them. “The past,” as Samantha says in the 2013 movie Her, “is just a story that we tell ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/Her-Catherine-Theodore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Scene from Her (2013)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that interpretation is a subjective activity, and because of this, it is something that you have complete power over. How you choose to create meaning from the events in your life is just that- a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to leave you with an alternate story about early humanity, one that vanished with the collapse of the cities of Mesopotamia: &lt;em&gt;The Epic of Gilgamesh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Epic of Gilgamesh&lt;/em&gt; describes a king named Gigamesh, and a wild man named Enkidu who was created by the gods to stop Gilgamesh from oppressing the people of Uruk. Enkidu arrives to Uruk, and challeges Gilgamesh to a competition, which Gilgamesh wins. The two become friends, and they go on many adventures together. But as a punishment of the their adventures, the gods sentence Enkidu to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gigamesh- desolated by the loss of his friend, and suddenly aware of his own mortality- takes a long and perilous journey in search of eternal life. He discovers that he cannot live forever, but that hummankind will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Stephen Greenblatt describes it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This is the great epic that circulated in the Near East for many centuries before the Hebrews decided to write their account of humankind’s earliest days: a tale of joyous sexual initiation; a gradual ascent from wildness to civility; a celebration of the city as a great good place; a difficult, reluctant acceptance of mortality; above all, a life that has at its center the experience not of marriage and family but of deep same-sex friendship.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/Gislebertus-Temptation-Of-Eve.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gislebertus, The Temptation of Eve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What are the events that are most significant in your life? If you were to name one, what would it be? Take a second, and think of one. I want you to keep it in the back of your mind as we consider the effects of a shared story that is exceptionally significant to humanity: the story of Adam and Eve.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/michelangelo-creation-of-adam.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Phantom Thread: Love and Desire</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/18/Desire-Phantom-Thread" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phantom Thread: Love and Desire" /><published>2018-01-18T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-18T11:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/18/Desire-Phantom-Thread</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/18/Desire-Phantom-Thread">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Phantom Thread, and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“When you &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt;, how does it feel? And when you &lt;strong&gt;desire&lt;/strong&gt;, how is it different?”&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;em&gt;Esther Perel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phantom Thread is a film about the relationship between Reynolds Woodcock, an English couture dressmaker from the 1950’s, and Alma, his most recent romantic interest. The film begins with the world that Reynolds inhabits- one where he is the center of attention of many women, and where his attention is solely focused on his work. Reynolds is a man of particular habits- ones that Alma will later describe as “fussy”- and has a sensitive relationship with his work, which he connects to his childhood and his mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Alma first appears, she is a waitress at a countryside restaurant. They circle one another with wandering eyes, and Reynolds asks her to dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alma experiences many of Reynold’s peculiarities right away: from his fixation on his deceased mother, his sister’s inattention to privacy, and Reynold’s singular focus on dress-making. However, during the series of uncomfortable interactions, it is revealed that she does not think much of herself, but Reynolds finds her to be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-alma.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alma in an extravagant pink dress&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, she begins to discover more about their relationship, as well as Reynold’s lifestyle. She loves his attention at first, her eyes following him as he organizes little details in the fabric as he dresses her like a doll. But then, she begins to feel more and more like a doll, a disposable object, a lifeless toy that can be cast into a corner without a second thought. Reynolds is surrounded by fawning women, and Alma begins to experience a growing jealousy from within her. His peculiar nature is undirected, but distant, and almost feels spiteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She discovers that he is weak after exhausting himself with his passion for dressmaking, and that he needs her most in his weakness. After an argument over dinner, she decides to poison Reynolds with a concoction of mushrooms in tea. He falls ill over the next day. After she nurses him back to health, he realizes that he is missing something from a shared life, and asks her to marry him in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is an account of Reynold’s distaste for her habits and his cruel lashing as he begins to experience jealousy himself. The story ends with a repeating cycle of Alma’s poisoning and nursing Reynolds back to health- the two of them knowing that they will come back to each other when they are weak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-diner-scene.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reynolds asks Alma to dinner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you reconcile the opposing needs of love and desire? This crisis is at the center of modern relationships and comes from our demand for both within a single relationship. Psychotherapist Esther Perel says that we want the security and stability of a committed relationship, but also the adventure of desire. Desire, which is sustained by mystery and discovery, opposes the quality of immutability in a committed relationship. And it is from these opposing forces that we see the characters of Phantom Thread struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their jealousy, which ebbs and flows over the course of their relationship, is one of the more tangible forms of desire that we witness. Whenever Reynolds loses himself in his work, Alma feels a growing distance, and whenever Alma acts in a way that Reynolds does not anticipate, he feels unwanted. However, this is something that he understands about himself, whether or not he has control over it. “Marriage would make me deceitful, and I don’t ever want that”, he says. When Alma asks him more about it, he explains that expectations of others is dangerous, and results in a loss of control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-alma-on-stairs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alma on the staircase&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expectations can make you deceitful because you will try to push someone toward the mold you have created for them without realizing it, simply because you expect certain behavior. It is in the nature of expectation that this occurs, because we are limited in how we understand anything outside of ourselves, yet love pushes us to try to understand. We can develop some reasonable level of understanding, but to completely understand another person is impossible. When there is no end to the nuances in your own behavior, how can you expect to fully understand another’s?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alma acts on her jealousy by poisoning Reynolds, physically forcing him to need her. “I want you flat on your back. Helpless, tender, open with only me to help,” she says. His poison, on the other hand, is in the flailing anger in his words, and the cold disposition he applies toward her. They both carry the same need of being needed, and frivolousness with the love of the other. And in their inability to use words to express these things, a pattern emerges- a cycle of love and desire, of needing and being needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps in recognizing this cycle that their relationship begins to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine read tarot cards for me a few weeks back while she visited from Germany. One of the cards she drew was called the “Wheel of Fortune”, which contained a picture of a wheel with entities moving up one side and down the other. The meaning, she explained, was that by recognizing the cyclical nature of things, we can can take more control over our fates. When you are at the bottom of the wheel- at the low points in life- by remembering that it is part of a larger cycle, the virtue of patience can remind you to endure the bad and continue your search for the good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These cycles do not only occur within relationships of course, and Alma even says, “being in love with him makes life no great mystery.” Perhaps it is in recognizing the ups and downs, and in accepting that we cannot fully understand others, that we can build meaningful relationships where we can love, change, desire, and share a life with another person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/phantom-thread-end-credits.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alma being fitted for a dress by Reynolds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Phantom Thread, and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/phantom-thread.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern Relationships and Murakami’s Sputnik Sweetheart</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/books/media/writing/philosophy/2018/01/15/Modern-Relationships-and-Murakamis-Sputnik-Sweetheart" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern Relationships and Murakami's Sputnik Sweetheart" /><published>2018-01-15T13:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T13:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/books/media/writing/philosophy/2018/01/15/Modern-Relationships-and-Murakamis-Sputnik-Sweetheart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/books/media/writing/philosophy/2018/01/15/Modern-Relationships-and-Murakamis-Sputnik-Sweetheart">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the book Sputnik Sweetheart, and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of the word “Longing”, what do you think about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine hands reaching toward one another, their skin never touching. Or standing on some towering building and looking for the small shape of a place I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think of someone particular when you hear that word? Or is it a place that you haven’t been?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Murakami’s &lt;em&gt;Sputnik Sweetheart&lt;/em&gt;, every character is a satellite- a small, metal object, hurling through the emptiness of space. The narrator, who is in love with Sumire, watches as she falls in love with an older woman named Miu, who she refers to as her “Sputnik Sweetheart”. They are all intimate with one another in different ways, but between each of them, an uncrossible distance remains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And it came to me then. That we were wonderful traveling companions but in the end no more than lonely lumps of metal in their own separate orbits. From far off they look like beautiful shooting stars, but in reality they’re nothing more than prisons, where each of us is locked up alone, going nowhere. When the orbits of these two satellites of ours happened to cross paths, we could be together. Maybe even open our hearts to each other. But that was only for the briefest moment. In the next instant we’d be in absolute solitude. Until we burned up and became nothing.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sputnik referred to in the story is Sputnik 2, a Russian satellite that was launched into orbit in 1957 with a dog named Laika as its passenger. The word “Sputnik” enters the story from a miscommunication between Miu and Sumire, and is lovingly used to refer to Miu. When thinking of the same little satellite, the narrator pictures the dog gazing out into the “infinite loneliness of space”, looking for something in the blackness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These images set the tone of the story early on, and we watch as the characters pass out of each other’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/sputnik-laika.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Laika in the Sputnik 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did you write when you last wrote about someone you know? For me, it was during the last snowstorm, and I was in my room, watching the spotted darkness pass over my window. I wrote about a girl with brown hair that I once walked through the Isabella Stewart Gardner museum with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum has an interesting history: beginning with Gardner’s will for the building to never change after her death, and later involving a theft in the 1990’s. When you visit, now, you’ll find empty spaces in walls with the shadows of paintings, and frames with nothing in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote about the time we walked through those halls on a summer night, when she admired the old frames, while I was captivated by the empty spaces. Now, whenever I go, I feel like a ghost, searching for lost time- still captivated by the empty spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murakami writes in the same ways. His characters are always recurring in his novels- a man who has affairs with older women, a girl who stares at the moon- and are written as if he knew them. The metaphors he uses feel like memories rather than just imagery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Who can really distinguish the sea and what’s reflected in it? Or tell the difference between the falling rain and loneliness?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His intimacy with these characters feels like the written form of the kind of thoughts that come at night. I can imagine him laying in his bed, awake- his eyes staring at the ceiling- before he turns on a lamp at his bedside to write down a passing thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/sputnik-murakami.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Murakami&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease in which modern relationships comprise of missed connections is a paradox that is concerning to me. When Murakami published this book in 2001- five years after the rise of the mobile phone- the rate in which the world was becoming connected by technology had become exponential. Three years later, Facebook was introduced, and grew into a world-wide phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1960’s Stanley Milgram ran the “small world experiment”, in which the theory of &lt;em&gt;Six Degrees Of Separation&lt;/em&gt; was examined. In the theory, everyone in the world is connected by five intermediate acquaintances- so that if I count all my friends, friend’s friend’s, and so on, I would be connected to all 7 billion people on the planet. In 2011, Facebook analyzed their data, and found that this number is decreasing- from six degrees to five- and is continuing to do so as we become more connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a common complaint that I hear is that people are becoming lonelier as we become more connected. An article I read theorized that by being connected to so many people, individuals have become interchangable, and therefore connections are less durable than before. We know that we are connected to others, and so, we neglect to maintain our relationships over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of me wonders if we are fated to be the same kinds of characters that pass through the world of &lt;em&gt;Sputnik Sweetheart&lt;/em&gt;. There are many people that have passed in and out of my life, and on occasion, I wonder if our paths will cross again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think that I believe in fate. How I cultivate my relationships has always been a choice, either through instinct or through premeditated intention. And after a few years of choosing to find each other again, you know who is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think of those that leave marks on my life and never return, I know that over time, I’ll find myself  thinking like the narrator at the end of the story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We’re both looking at the same moon, in the same world. We’re connected to reality by the same line. All I have to do is draw it toward me. I spread my fingers and stare at the palms of both hands, looking for bloodstains. There aren’t any. No scent of blood, no stiffness. The blood must have already, in its own, silent way, seeped inside.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laika was the first animal in space, and died from a lack of oxygen on the sixth day of her orbit. In the U.S.S.R., on that same day, Khrushchev said “Now, our first Sputnik is not lonely in its space travels.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/sputnik-painting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Art for Sputnik Sweetheart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the book Sputnik Sweetheart, and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/sputnik.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Columbus: What happens when you meet your reflection?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/10/Columbus-What-Happens-When-You-Meet-Your-Reflection" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Columbus: What happens when you meet your reflection?" /><published>2018-01-10T08:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-10T08:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/10/Columbus-What-Happens-When-You-Meet-Your-Reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/film/media/philosophy/2018/01/10/Columbus-What-Happens-When-You-Meet-Your-Reflection">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Columbus, and contains important plot points from it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a famous black-and-white optical illusion called Rubin’s vase, where the subject changes from a white vase to the shadows of lovers when you choose to focus on the darkness. This phenomenon, called multistable perception, involves mutually exclusive perspectives that are unified in a single image. In &lt;em&gt;Columbus&lt;/em&gt;, a place where people are seen in reflections and through mirrors, this duality can be seen in everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Columbus&lt;/em&gt; is a film written and directed by Kogonada, following Jin, a Korean man with a dying father, and Casey, a 19-year old who forewent college to take care of her mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-jin-in-rain.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jin, walking through the rain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jin, played by John Cho, reluctantly arrives in Columbus upon news of his father’s admittance to the hospital. During his first few days, he wanders aimlessly, talking on the phone to his employer overseas. As he interacts with the people around him, we learn about the way he sees his father: distant, and loved by many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He believes that his father does not need him, and draws away from him for those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-casey.png&quot; alt=&quot;Casey outside of the library&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey, played by Haley Lu Richardson, is a native to Columbus. When we first meet her, she recites facts about the surrounding architecture under her breath as she smokes. She practices a monologue about a building that is asymmetrical, but balanced- one that she repeats to Jin later on. Over time, we also learn about her relationship with her parent. She sees her mother as someone who is abandoned, loved only by her, and needs her. Casey decides not to go to college for these same reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-mirrors.png&quot; alt=&quot;Casey and Jin staring at their reflections&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lens is focused on architecture, and thus draws our attention to the environments that our characters are confined in. In Jin’s eyes, we find a stifling little town, filled with familiar sights. “You grow up around something and it feels like nothing”, he says. When he describes a psychiatric ward as “both a phyiscal bridge, and a metaphorical one”, we find that the description is his father’s, and he does not believe in his father’s idea of the healing ability of architecture. He sees it as grandiose and egocentric, as a delusion of architects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Casey, on the other hand, recounts a memory where she discovered the beauty in her surroundings during a difficult time in her life. She has experienced the healing ability that Jin’s father speaks of, and expresses her love to her mother in the same way- through creating a caring environment for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like water, they fill the space that they exist in. But while both of them are in Columbus, the shapes that they form are completely different. They are opposites- young and old, selfless and self-absorbed- meeting at a place and time where they are best able to learn from their differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-bridge-conversation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jin and Casey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of their relationship, when Casey gives Jin a tour of the area, he has no interest in the architecture. Instead, he asks her to tell him what she cares about- rather than the facts that she has memorized. In watching her fascination of architecture- and through it, her great capacity to love- he learns that he has a choice to care in the same ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through Jin, Casey is reminded that people make their own choices, even with the ease of a good environment. Independence is something that we all have, whether or not we choose it, and Jin acts as an example that she should make the best of her own. Casey would otherwise live a life with lingering regrets, and perhaps in the teeth of time, her ability to love would slowly be consumed. Jin explicitly reminds Casey that her mother wants what is best for her, and Casey eventually chooses to pursue a career in architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A missed connection is a tragic thing- a fact that both Jin and Casey understand in different contexts. We all have our own differences and because of this, we have a lot that we can learn from one another. And so, the two push one another to examine themselves and share, and a beautiful intimacy grows between them, like the shape of a vase between two shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-car.png&quot; alt=&quot;Casey and Jin admiring architecture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the course of the film, Jin searches for what he believes is a tower in his father’s diary. He tries to decipher the undescriptive scrawl of lines as he wanders the city, searching for a building that matches it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the film, as he shares a bag of pastries with Casey, he points at an empty space created by two brick walls. He’s unsure, but he believes that he has found the location that his father wrote about. It is not the tower that he expected, but instead, a space between two structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he settles into an apartment in Columbus to take care of his father, Casey says her goodbyes before leaving to college. Two people, from different worlds- each a reflection of the other- converged, then passed through to the other side, leaving both lives a little fuller than they were before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/columbus-tower.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jin, looking for the tower in his father's diary with Casey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Spoiler Alert: this post is about the film Columbus, and contains important plot points from it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/columbus.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning SEO: Moving up my page rank - part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning SEO: Moving up my page rank - part 1" /><published>2018-01-07T02:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T02:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2018/01/07/Learning-SEO-Increasing-Page-Rank-Part-1">&lt;p&gt;Since my last post on SEO, I was able to make (relatively) significant progress with my SEO. Here, I want to talk about the &lt;strong&gt;progress&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve made, &lt;strong&gt;how I made the progress&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;next steps&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the start of my blog, I’ve been able to ramp up my viewership from &lt;strong&gt;0 users to 131 unique users&lt;/strong&gt;. These are not recurring visitors, which is what I eventually want, but they are visitors just the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see that there is a &lt;strong&gt;very high bounce rate&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll discuss this in a next steps portion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I was able to increase my page rank in searches for my full name. This means that when people look up “Elias Fong” on Google, they are more likely to see this site as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleSearchByName.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Search for Elias Fong&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I re-created the site for this URL (it was just a portfolio site in the past), the search result for this site was on the third page of results. We’ll discuss keyword optimization in a &lt;em&gt;next steps&lt;/em&gt; portion as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-i-made-the-progress&quot;&gt;How I made the progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with viewership. This part is a less impressive (to me) than my progress on page rankings, simply because I know the effort it took to reach this level of views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Google analytics, there is a nifty widget that shows the pages that people visited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-PageViews.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Page Views&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that there is a large number of views for one page, and a lot less for the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page with the most views is my post on &lt;em&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/em&gt;. At the time that I’m writing this, Call Me By Your Name is getting a lot of Oscars hype as a movie, and there is even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/callmebyyourname/&quot;&gt;Reddit community&lt;/a&gt; around the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I posted a link to the post in the reddit community, as well as on my facebook, and this is the traffic that I got from it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Channels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google Analytics Sources&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is when the post went public, and the second was a private release to my friends to proofread the post. You can see that the majority of the visits come from reddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, the viewership drops as the post gets older. I was unable to find other channels to publicize my post, so the only thing I did was reach out to communities that might have interest in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my &lt;strong&gt;page rank&lt;/strong&gt;, it is very important to note that the increase in rank is in searches for “Elias Fong”. I have not done any other tests yet, but ideally, I want to target certain keywords and increase my page rank on those searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is a good proof of concept for myself, and I was able to do that through &lt;em&gt;communication with Google&lt;/em&gt;. This means that I added meta tags and structured json to my page to make it easier for Google to understand what it was about, added a link to my site in all my social media to increase the number of inbound links to my site, and submitted a sitemap to Google Webmaster Tools to make it easier for Google to index my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above, I noted several things that need improvement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a high bounce rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Page rank in other keyword searches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recurring viewership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I haven’t defined it in a previous post, the bounce rate refers to the portion of people that view one page in your site, and leave without viewing any other pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the majority of my views are from my &lt;em&gt;Call Me By Your Name&lt;/em&gt; post, it makes sense to me that viewers read the post and left right after. That being said, we may be able to improve this by adding a list of related posts to the end of each post, so that users are more likely to view another page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a lower bounce rate may help with maintaning a recurring viewership. If users feel like they like a significant amount of your content (and not just one page), they are probably more likely to come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For page rank in other keyword searches, an important thing to think about is what keywords I want to target. Are there specific people I want to see my blog? By determining who I want to find my blog, I can think about the ways they would search for what they might find on my blog, and use wording that is more relevant to those searches in my page content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally for recurring viewership, I need to develop consistency in my blog. I need to have a significant amount of content around similar topics, so that a particular user will find multiple things that they want to read on my site, as well as have a reasonable expectation that I will post more similar content. Part of this will be me, following my SEO, and the other part will be showing my new content consistently to specific channels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Since my last post on SEO, I was able to make (relatively) significant progress with my SEO. Here, I want to talk about the progress I’ve made, how I made the progress, and next steps.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/posts/01-07-GoogleAnalytics-Channels.png" /></entry></feed>