<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-31T17:41:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Elias Fong</title><subtitle>Personal site of a Elias Fong, a developer based out of Boston,  containing tutorials, reviews, and other posts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Designing a Personal Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing a Personal Site" /><published>2017-12-31T16:49:29-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-31T16:49:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/design/2017/12/31/designing-a-personal-site">&lt;p&gt;When I first started working on this site, I found the first steps of the process very difficult. How do you reduce yourself into a few words and a layout? How do you express who you are without being self-centered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are a lot of established design processes for these types of problems. The first is &lt;strong&gt;defining use cases&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply put, &lt;em&gt;how do I want my site to be used&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was mainly focused on a few cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find links to my projects/media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can see my face (somewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can read about my ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these priorities in mind, I started thinking about what I want my first impression to be, and ended up with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;current banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This came from a variety of motivations. First, I wanted to have a &lt;em&gt;picture of my face&lt;/em&gt;, in order to &lt;strong&gt;keep things personal&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/eliasInTheSun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old picture of me&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is from a &lt;em&gt;long time ago&lt;/em&gt; (don’t judge), but I really like the colors in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;explain a bit about who I am&lt;/em&gt;, I added the &lt;strong&gt;little blurb&lt;/strong&gt;, which conveniently &lt;strong&gt;links&lt;/strong&gt; to a lot of &lt;em&gt;ME things&lt;/em&gt; (like my github and instagram):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner-blurb.png&quot; alt=&quot;site banner blurb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it also has a &lt;em&gt;link to my posts&lt;/em&gt;, which are just posted below it on the home page. I chose to make it a blog because it would &lt;strong&gt;allow the site to evolve as I learn/consume new things&lt;/strong&gt; (okay, also because I wanted to blog).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The background is a picture I took on a trip in Italy that I tinted down to make the blurb easier to read. There’s a &lt;strong&gt;trend&lt;/strong&gt; in visual design centered around using more &lt;em&gt;large images&lt;/em&gt;, and its valuable to &lt;strong&gt;share a visual language with your peers&lt;/strong&gt;, in order to &lt;strong&gt;stay current&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All together, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/original-site-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;site banner background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That covers the first two things: having links to my projects, and a picture of my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great! Now for expressing my ideas in blog form. What are the use cases here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find the posts on google&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I plan to write about a variety of topics,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts with a certain topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because of my goal of expanding my online presence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can subscribe to my blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll write more about SEO&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;building a blog with jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; in a later post, and for now, we’ll &lt;em&gt;focus on design&lt;/em&gt;. Let’s start with the list of posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/post-link-image.png&quot; alt=&quot;post entry&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to have the list of posts on the home page, so that visitors can get straight to the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each post has an image (for visual engagement), and a title/description to show the content. I also added tags so that the user can navigate to similar posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/subscription-box.png&quot; alt=&quot;subscription box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also added a subscription widget at the bottom of every page, so that I can grow a base of readers. I’m using &lt;strong&gt;mailchimp to manage the subscription&lt;/strong&gt;, which I’ll cover in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And altogether, I have a personal site that includes a blog and covers the following use cases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can find links to my projects/media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can see my face (somewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can read about my ideas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can browse a list of posts with a certain topic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visitors can subscribe to my blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I first started working on this site, I found the first steps of the process very difficult. How do you reduce yourself into a few words and a layout? How do you express who you are without being self-centered?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/mirimar.jpg" /></entry></feed>